[Music]
hi everyone this is Ravi welcome to
prenti stasa automation tutorial as you
all know I have already published 74
YouTube videos covering beginners level
intermediate level and advanced level
concepts of test automation by using
tricentis tasa from few videos onwards
have started teaching you the realtime
scenarios where you might encounter
different types of obstacles and how can
you solve those obstacles while
automating the test cases by using
trient
tasa please do subscribe to the channel
click on Bell icon you'll receive
notifications whenever I publish more
videos and don't forget to like and
share the video
thank
you this is our lesson 75 in terms of
overall trient Taska Automation and it
is our obstacle 33 in terms of realtime
scenarios so in this lesson I'm going to
teach you how can we solve an
obstacle where you need to play a game
by using tricentis tasa with the help
help of loops and conditions method and
send Keys method so now let us see in
detail what is the obstacle that we are
going to solve
for so here are the obstacles that we
are solving from few videos onwards and
today's obstacle is trient TSA Olympics
which is categorized as hard let us go
for
it what is the obstacle we need to solve
so we need to basically play this game
by using trient tasa we need to
automate playing the game so how can we
do that let me show you what is the game
so you can see here here are the
instructions that it is going to display
as soon as you click on
start here a person is going to do ice
skating and it tree comes either left
side or right side and your instruction
is going to show you whether to move
left or right how are we going to move
left or right by using the keyboard
right arrow and left Arrow let's click
on start if you see the instruction go
left go right go left go right go left
so basically I'm just clicking on the
right and left Arrow based on the
instructions that are displaying so we
need to automate by using tasa to play
the game so how can we do that let us go
back to tr
tasa before that let me just click on
try again right let's keep the screen
here let's go back to tasar as usual we
are going to start working on module
section right side right click on this
obstacles folder scan
application now select the application
you would like to scan and click on
scan if you see here we need to capture
two objects one is start button and the
instructions that are displaying to play
the game either go left right or if if
your game is over then it's going to say
you did
it and then if you failed to play the
game it's going to say you got crashed
so basically I need to capture these
instructions as well as the start button
for that you can see here there is a
start button which is uniquely
identified but I don't see these
instructions so for that let's expand
the filter here click on this and click
one more time so now you can see here
this is the instruction prepare for the
start this is the instruction right so
select this
instruction and make sure to select the
right proper properties so here for that
for this div component this is basically
a div element right so here I would like
to use ID and then tag as div I don't
want to use inner text so uncheck this
one so basically for this div element I
want to use ID text tag div okay so once
we capture these two objects now name
the module as
your obstacle name name the module as
obstacle name copy the
obstacle then paste it here and now save
the
module and then close your xcan so let
us go back to trient tasa and scroll
down to the bottom so this is the
obstacle that we captured just now
double click on this to make sure it
shows give and start button so here the
instructions keep changing right so I
don't want to keep the instruction as it
is but I just I would like to rename
this as div okay so once that is done
now let us start automating the test
case so right click on this obstacles
test case folder and create test
case and then paste the same obstacle
name that we captured earlier and then
double click on this now let us start
automating so what is the first action
that we need to perform our first action
is you have to click on start button so
for that I'm going to Simply drag this
and drop onto my test
case then I'm going to name this as this
particular step as start the game
start
the
G and then so what I'm going to do I'm
going to click on start button so for
that enter the value again start button
as X which performs click action so once
that is done I'm going to start using
two statement why because I have to
perform left arrow and right arrow
multiple times until the game is over or
until you crash the game right so these
are the two possibilities is so always I
have to click on left arrow on the
keyboard or right arrow on the keyboard
so this is a loop so that's why I'm
going to use here right click on your
test
case and then select create do
statement so once I click on start now
I'm going to say I'm going to name this
as
while there is
is a tree so whenever there is a tree
you need to either perform left keyboard
operation or right arrow keyboard
operation so here what I'm going to do
under loop I would like to introduce an
if condition
here create if statement so what I'm
going to do here
now under Loop so I'm going to name this
loop
as turn so what I'm doing here under
Loop I'm basically turning either left
or right how are going to how are we
going to identify whether to turn left
or right I'm going to tell you now okay
if the
tree is on right side the tree is on
right side you need to click on left
Arrow right so for that what I'm going
to do here under condition drag this
module and drop onto the
condition so okay let me do one thing
let me rename this
as where is the
tree and my condition first condition is
to verify
is free on the
on the right
side if the tree is on right side what
should I do I should click on left Arrow
so for that how do you know if the tree
is on right side or Not by seeing the
instruction if the tree is on right side
you are going to get instruction as go
left if the tree is on left side then
you will get instruction as go right
right so now that's why what I'm going
to do I'm going to verify the inner text
of this div inner text so basically your
action mode should be first
verify and come back to the
value inner
text equal
to if the inner text is equal to
go
left if the inner text is is equal to go
lift then what should I perform I have
to click on right arrow in the keyboard
for that under then I would like to call
ADD test step I'm going to use tbox send
keys and here under caption so what is
the caption of the window my caption of
the window is caption of the window is
PR and obstacle course and so on what
I'm going to do
rentis
obstacle I'm going to use regular
expression trient is obstacle okay that
is my window caption and then here I
need to send a
key
left so done I'm sending a key left
and
then if the tree is on right side then
you are clicking on
left what if the tree is left side for
that for the same if condition I'm going
to insert right click on this if
condition you can see here this is your
if condition and then insert create L
statement so I'm going to say here if
the tree
is
on left
side then again now what I'm going to do
again I'm going to call send
Keys ADD test step T box send
Keys again
here let us take the caption of the
window from here
and this time you need to click you need
to click on
right need to click on right
key R
GD let me again R
GD open sorry close curly braces and
then close these double codes so what
I'm doing to send a key basically Double
C double codes open curly bases left
close curvy bases and then close double
quotes in the same way right so I have
to perform
this either left or right based on your
instruction until when
until this condition is met so this is
your Loop and this is your condition
sorry this is your Loop and this is your
condition we finished Loop now what is
the condition just drag the subst strule
again module and drop on to condition
what is the condition until I get the
instruction this should repeat until I
don't get the instruction as trash or
you did it right so here what I'm going
to do again I'm going to use
verify and then here I'm going to
capture the inner text inner
text not equal to repeat this until
inner text not equal to I'm going to use
the regular expression open curly bracis
reg
X
either your
instruction should be crash or pipe
symbol
you did
it and then close your double
codes close
your Square
Braes and close your curly Braes you can
see here I'm using the regular
expression this instruction div should
not have an inner text of crash or you
did it that means this Loop will be
continuing until it has left right left
right instruction as soon as you get the
instruction or crash or you did it it's
going to stop the
loop okay so now let us change the work
state of this test case as
completed save the test
case now let me explain what we did okay
so what we did first we simply use the
module to to click on start button and
then I have introduced a do statement
which will have Loop and the condition
under Loop I'm using if
statement to find out where is the
tree if the tree is on right side I'll
be getting the instruction as go lift
here if I get the instruction as go left
then I'm sending a key left key if the
tree is on left side then I need to
click on right so because my first
condition is go left then I'm clicking
on left else what is the next condition
it will be right so I need not to again
verify inner text go right right so I'm
basically using the else condition so
this needs to be repeated until it finds
the instruction as crash or you did it
so now let us run this before I run let
me click on try
again and now let us run the test
case right click
on right click on test case and running
scratchbook now it's going to start
playing the game you can see here go
left it is clicking on left go right it
is again clicking on right go left it's
going to complete the entire
game so it's crashed let's see what
happened okay let's go back here
now so what we missed is here if you see
it is repeating until 30 times only
after that it is not repeating so that
means I have to basically increase this
limit
to loop I have to increase how select
this do
statement open the properties so you can
see maximum repetitions allowed is 30 I
would like to make this as
100 now you save the test
case so don't forget to increase the
limit of your two Loop property okay so
now if I run the test case again
let's try again now if I run the test
case now it is going to play entire
game so now it started playing go right
it clicked on right go left it is
clicking on left Arrow so it's going to
complete the entire
game as soon as it finds the instruction
as you did it it's going to stop see
here we got the instruction as good job
you solve this automation problem
because it came as because the message
came as you did
it so hope you all understand the
concept so if you see here the loop
repeated almost like 44 times so after
44th time the game is over and then you
did
it so if you have any queries leave your
queries in the comment box I'll try to
respond to your queries thank you thank
you hope you all understand how can we
solve an obstacle where you need to play
a game by using tricentis
TSA with the help of loops and condition
methods and send Keys
method please do subscribe to the
channel click on Bell icon you'll
receive notifications whenever I publish
more videos don't forget to like and
share the video thank you
[Music]